# Sergiy Kochenko Junior Full Stack Developer

sergiykochenko@gmail.com • +353 873407890 • Tralee, Co. Kerry, Ireland
github • linkedin • My Website Resume

## **Executive Summary**

Junior Software Developer with a Diploma in Full-stack Software Development from the Code Institute/Kerry College. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Python. I have 15 years of experience in Maritime Service. I am a valuable team player with strong communication skills and effective problem-solving abilities. I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

#### **Education**

November 2022–May 2023 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Tralee, Ireland (Credit Rated by Kerry College)

February 2022–May 2022 Diploma of QA/QC Engineer

Online University TOMMY - Odesa, Ukraine

September 2008–July 2012 Diploma of Bachelor's degree

**Marine Transportation** 

Odesa National Maritime Academy (ONMA) - Odesa, Ukraine

September 2003–July 2006 Diploma of Junior Specialist

**Marine Transportation** 

I.O. Marinesko Odesa Maritime - Odesa, Ukraine

September 1996–July 1999 Diploma of Junior Specialist

Transportation and Logistics Management

I.O. Marinesko Odesa Maritime - Odesa, Ukraine

**Technical Skillset** 

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python3

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres, AWS, Cloudinary

Frameworks: Django, jQuery, Bootstrap

Version Control: Git, Github, Codeanywhere, Replit

### **Portfolio projects**

#### 1. Portfolio Project 1

**Technology Used** - HTML5 and CSS.

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/SergiyKochenko/SergiyKochenko

Live Site - <a href="https://sergiykochenko.github.io/SergiyKochenko/">https://sergiykochenko.github.io/SergiyKochenko/</a>

#### 2. Portfolio Project 2

**Technologies Used** - HTML5, CSS and JavaScript. **GitHub Repo** - <a href="https://github.com/SergiyKochenko/ProjectTwo">https://github.com/SergiyKochenko/ProjectTwo</a> **Live Site** - <a href="https://sergiykochenko.github.io/ProjectTwo/">https://sergiykochenko.github.io/ProjectTwo/</a>

#### 3. Portfolio Project 3

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS and Python3.

GitHub Repo - <a href="https://github.com/SergiyKochenko/atm-bunking-app">https://github.com/SergiyKochenko/atm-bunking-app</a>

Live Site - <a href="https://atm-bunking-app.herokuapp.com/">https://atm-bunking-app.herokuapp.com/</a>

### 4. Portfolio Project 4

**Technologies Used** - HTML5, CSS, Python3, JavaScript and Unit test. **GitHub Repo** - <a href="https://github.com/SergiyKochenko/portfolio-project-four-live-roject-four-https://app-portfolio-project-four-herokuapp.com/">https://app-portfolio-project-four-herokuapp.com/</a>

# 5. Portfolio Project 5 eCommerce

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS, Python3, JavaScript and Unit test.

GitHub Repo - <a href="https://github.com/SergiyKochenko/pp5-house-stock-ecommerce-berokuapp.com/">https://github.com/SergiyKochenko/pp5-house-stock-ecommerce-berokuapp.com/</a>

Live Site - <a href="https://pp5-house-stock-ecommerce-berokuapp.com/">https://pp5-house-stock-ecommerce-berokuapp.com/</a>

#### **Work Experience**

March 2022-Present

# QA/QC Engineer

Ubertesters, Freelancer, Remote

- IT methodologies, test cases, checklists, defect management,
- Testing strategies and approaches, test levels, requirements analysis,
- Performance testing, databases.

August 2006–February 2022

#### **Maritime Service**

V. Ships, World Wide

- Deck Cadet (2006) Learn Documentation in the Maritime industry on board vessels.
- 3rd Officer (2006 2011) Maintenance of safety equipment, navigation on the sea, documentation and cargo operation.
- 2nd Officer (2011 2019) Maintenance of navigation equipment (Nav. Officer), navigation on the sea, documentation, cargo operation and in charge of radio communication (Radio Officer).
- Chief Officer (2019 2022) Safety Officer, in charge of cargo operation, in charge of carrying cargo on board vessels, in charge of cargo calculation, navigation when a vessel is at sea, Ship Security Officer, in charge of Safety Meetings and drills, Team Leader.

# **Interests/Additional Information**

Currently studying the online course with Zero To Mastery Academy learning "Complete React Developer (w/ Redux, Hooks, GraphQL)" - and working on my 6th project eCommerce webshop.
 GitHub Repo - <a href="https://github.com/SergivKochenko/crwn-clothing">https://github.com/SergivKochenko/crwn-clothing</a>